Anirudhan J. Rajagopalan

 $\label{linkedin.com/in/rajegannathan} I inkedin.com/in/rajegannathan github.com/rajegannathan$

Summary

Software Engineer with around 5 years of experience. Currently pursuing Masters in Computer Science at New York University. Skills include Full stack Web application development (python, java, ruby on rails, angularjs), Deep Learning (torch), and Machine Learning (python, numpy, sklearn). I am interested in using Machine Learning to solve real world problems.

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science

Dec 2016

Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University.

CGPA 3.75/4.0

Course List: Deep Learning, GPU — Architecture & Programming, Computational Machine Learning, Foundational Machine Learning, Web Search Engine, Realtime & Big data analysis.

Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

May 2010

Government College of Technology, Coimbatore

CGPA 8.01/10.0

Academic Projects

2015 - 2016

Improving classification accuracy on STL-10 dataset.

Correlation analysis of taxi ridership and public events.

Torch (Deep Learning)

Used convolutional clustering on around 100K unlabelled images to learn the first layer of features used in the convolutional network. This improved the classification accuracy by 2%.

Grasp & Lift Detection.

Python, Numpy, Scipy, HPC

Used \mathbf{VLAD} feature representation and SVMs for the multi class classification problem of detecting a person's hand movements from EEG signals.

Liver & Pancreatic carcenoma classification.

Python, Numpy, Scipy, HPC

We classified liver and pancreatic cancer using unbalanced DNA protein expression data. We got an accuracy of 97% inspite of having an unbalanced data with more features (500K) than the samples (700).

Spark, Hive, Python, HPC

Using NYC taxi ride dataset (26GB) and events data from Eventful API, we were able to find a 60% increase in the ridership of NYC taxis when a public event happens in the locality.

Work Experience

Around 5 years

Data Science Intern Eyenuk Inc, Los Angeles, CA. Jun 2016 — Aug 2016

- Explored the classification of Diabetic Retinopathy with Residual Networks against VGG.
- Setup a scalable production AWS deployment using VPC, Route 53, ELB, ACM, and RDS.

Software Consultant Canvera Technologies, BGL, IN. Jan 2014 — Sep 2014

- Performance Optimizations Load time: ~10 sec \rightarrow 1 sec. Asset size: ~1.5Mb \rightarrow ~600Kb.
- \bullet Setup the application architecture & development process. Mentored the development team.

Founding Member f1circle.com, HYD, IN. May 2013 — Nov 2013

- Built the complete application from scratch. (ROR, Angularjs, Memcached, Redis)
- Built Information extraction engine. It extracts name, place, & price info from user's posts.

Freelancer India. May 2013 — Jan 2015

- Implemented the common sign-on page, branding workflows and modal framework for Vera.
- Built Urblotter (app.urblotter.com) a betting website for FIFA 2014. (ROR, Angularjs).

Software Enginneer Insideview Inc, India Oct 2011 — May 2013

- Developed in-product notification framework using **Drools framework** & **Lucene indexes**.
- Built the Activitystream security framework using AWS Simpledb and custom eventbus.